Andrew Ellicott Douglass papers, 1867-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series III: University of Arizona, 1904-1962
  With but one important exception, no attempt has been made to segregate this material into sub-categories, or even to separate his correspondenc with other observatories or astronomers, because it is so inter-woven--both administratively and professionally. The exception, however, is the removal of all correspondence and material relating to his research on tree rings--a monumental endeavor carried on concurrently with all his other duties and activities. This material is so voluminous and specialized that it has been arranged separately, and will be found in boxes 64-84. Therefore, the user should remain aware that a large body of correspondence for this period (1908-1938) of Dr. Douglass's university years is filed elsewhere.
  The designation "correspondence" has been employed rather freely, for included also are personal notes pertaining to administration, official University communications from various offices, programs of University events attended by Dr. Douglass, and some clippings relating to University matters.
  Because budgets and annual reports of the Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory were inter-related and often made jointly, they have been placed together.
  - University of Arizona
    - Correspondence: University of Arizona brochures and reports at the time of A.E.D.'s arrival. 1906 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. 1905-1907 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1907-1908 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. 1908-1909 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence. 1909-1910 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence. 1910-1911 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. 1911-1912 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. 1912-1913 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. 1913-1914 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1914-1915 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1915 Desert (University of Arizona yearbook). 1915 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (I). 1915-1916 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (II). 1915-1916 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 1916 Desert (University of Arizona yearbook). 1916 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (I). 1916-1917 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (II). 1916-1917 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "The Colodny Affair." 1916-1917 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (I). 1917-1918 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (II). 1917-1918 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - 1918 Desert (University of Arizona yearbook). 1918 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. 1918-1919 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Financial Records. 1918-1919 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1919-1920 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Financial Records. 1919-1920 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (I). 1920-1921 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (II). 1920-1921 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Financial Records. 1920-1921 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (I). 1921-1922 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (II). 1921-1922 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Financial Records. 1921-1922 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. 1922-1923 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Financial Records. 1922-1923 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (I). 1923-1924 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (II). 1923-1924 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Financial Records. 1923-1924 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (I). 1924-1925 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (II). 1924-1925 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding the search for an Astronomy Assistant. 1922-1925 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (I). 1925-1926 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (II). 1925-1926 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence. 1926-1927 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. 1927-1928 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. 1928-1929 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1930-1931 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. 1931-1932 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (I). 1931-1932 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (II). 1931-1932 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. 1932-1933 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. 1933-1934 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. 1936-1937 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence. 1937-1938 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Physical Sciences Survey Course (plans, correspondence). 1933-1938 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Physical Sciences Survey Course (syllabi, lecture, and quiz topics). 1933-1938 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Physical Sciences Survey Course (astronomy lectures). 1933-1938 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Physical Sciences Survey Course (astronomy lecture "discards"). 1933-1938 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Physical Sciences Survey Course (books, reading lists). 1933-1938 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Committees: Faculty Treasurer. 1904-1911 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Committees: Administrative Committee. 1914-1925 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Committees: Committee on Social Life & Student Enterprises. 1914-1916 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Committees: Committee on Academic Tenure. 1916-1917 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Committees: Committee on Summer Session. 1918-1920 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Committees: Committee on Scholarships and Loans. 1919-1920 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Committees: Committee on Lecture & Laboratory Work. 1916-1917 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Committees: Committee on Student Assemblies. 1914-1916 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Committees: Committee on Student Assemblies. 1916-1918 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Committees: Committee on Student Assemblies. 1918-1925, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Committees: Curriculum Committee. 1911-1912 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Committees: Committee on Gifts. 1930-1936 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Committees: Miscellaneous Committees. 1923-1926 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes. 1911-1919 (Box 36)
    - Doctors' Academy of the University of Arizona. 1922-1923 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Club. 1916-1944 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Rifle Club. 1917-1918 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - University Club. 1914-1919 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Student Debates. 1915-1921 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - University week. 1914-1916, 1918, 1920 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Physics Questions for Country Scholarship Exam. 1916-1919 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - College of Letters, Arts and Sciences: Budget. 1917-1918 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Student Forum. 1931-1934 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - A.E.D.'s University of Arizona Appointments. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Christmas Cards, wedding announcements from faculty members. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with ex-president A.H. Wilde after he left the University. (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with ex-president von Kleinsmid after he left the University. (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Teachers' Agencies (brochures). 1908-1921 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Classes: Astronomy lectures. 1908-1930s (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Classes: Astronomy correspondence courses. 1916-1925 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Classes: Physics. 1908-1919 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Classes: Physics (financial records, notes). 1912-1922 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Classes: Physics & Astronomy Department inventories. 1912-1918 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Classes: Hydraulics notes. 1907 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Classes: Value of Gravity at the University. 1909, 1915-1916 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Classes: Class record books, 1-6. 1906-1918 (Box 38)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 1. 1919-1924, 1931-1933 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 1 ("Tycho Brahe Uproar"). 1920-1921 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 1S (summer school, Flagstaff). 1920 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 2 (class records). 1921-1922, 1932-1935 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 3 (class records). 1910-1921 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Astronomy Class Records: Astronomy 101 (class records). 1922-1935 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (former students): Dana K. Bailey. 1937 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (former students): Joseph F. Burns. 1909-1920 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (former students): J. Carl Cook. 1911-1917 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (former students): Frank L. Culin, Jr. 1915-1918, 1930, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (former students): William J. Done. 1925, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (former students): Loyd C. Elliott. 1914-1932 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (former students): Howard W. Estill & Edward H. Estill. 1917-1929 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (former students): Jo Fisher Freeman. 1920-1945 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (former students): J.W. Getsinger. 1916-1950 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence (former students): Duane A. Hawkins. 1926-1950 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (former students): Philip C. Keenan. 1930-1935 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (former students): E.A. Markham. 1916-1920 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (former students): A. Boyd Mewborn. 1944-1949 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence (former students): Alfred D. Micotti. 1920, 1930 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence (former students): George Nishihara. 1920-1958 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (former students): Temple F. Penrod. 1917-1919 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence (former students): Wainwright Randall. 1915-1922 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (former students): T.J. Randolph. 1918-1954 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (former students): Fred W. Rogers. 1913-1955 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence (former students): War-time correspondence with various students. 1916-1918 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: Committee papers and accounts. 1909-1924 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: Correspondence (Sunshine Recorder). 1909-1914 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: Correspondence (Sunshine Recorder). 1915-1924 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: "Measurement of Areas of Isolation." 1913-1923 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: various records. 1913-1918 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: various records. 1919, 1921 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: records (1 roll & rolls 1-8). 1900s-1920s (Box 42)
    - Douglas Fund Instrument: records (rolls 9-16). 1920s (Box 43)
  - Steward Observatory
    - The Harvard 8" telescope (correspondence relating to its loan and return, clippings, photographs, notes, drawings, sketches pertaining to its mounting and related equipment). 1908-1922 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Efforts to establish an observatory (correspondence and clippings). 1907-1911 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Efforts to establish an observatory (correspondence and clippings). 1914 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Efforts to establish an observatory (correspondence and clippings). 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Lavinia Steward and her gift (correspondence, clippings, photographs, drafts of initial publicity story. 1916 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Observatory site work (notes, tests, computations, reports to the President). 1916 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Plans and notes. 1916 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Construction correspondence. 1916 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Plans and notes. 1917 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Construction correspondence. 1917 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Plans, notes, correspondence. 1918 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Construction: correspondence. 1919 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Construction: plans and notes. 1919 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Construction: meridian tests for the 36". 1919-1920 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Construction: correspondence (dome). 1920 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Construction: correspondence (telescope mounting, dome, and glass and optical work). 1920 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Construction: trips East to inspect Telescope and Lens. 1921 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Construction: plans, notes, bills, correspondence, clippings. 1921 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Construction: correspondence. 1921 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Construction: clock study. August 1921 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Construction: photographs. 1919-1921 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Construction: correspondence. 1922 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Construction: notes, correspondence, clippings. 1922 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Construction: bills. 1922 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Construction: correspondence, notes, plans, bills. 1923 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Construction: dedication (correspondence, clippings, photographs, program). April 23, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Construction: adjustments on the 36". 1923-1924 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Construction: correspondence, equipment notes, etc. 1924 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Clippings. 1913-1929 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Clippings. 1930-1931 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Clippings. 1932-1963 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Photographs. 1922-1959 (Box 46a, Folder 10)
    - Negatives. 1919-1928, undated (Box 46a, Folder 10)
    - Budgets: proposals, notes, and approved budgets. 1919-1946 (Box 46b)
    - Reports. 1907-1946 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Steward Observatory," by A.E.D. Reprint from the Annual Report of the University of Arizona for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1939 (various drafts). 1939 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous historical materials. 1918-1957 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Search for Observatory site by the Smithsonian Institution (correspondence). 1918-1921 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Eclipse of the Sun. June 8, 1918 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Silvering notes and records. 1914-1936 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Eclipse of the Sun. January 24, 1925 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Observatory Fellowship (applications from and correspondence with various candidates). 1931-1933 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence. 1938-1943 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. 1943-1945 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. 1945-1951 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - "City Lights," (correspondence, clippings, notes, etc. relating to the Observatory's struggle to maintain suitable atmospheric conditions). 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Search for an Observatory site (correspondence). 1933-1939 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Searchfor an Observatory site (correspondence). 1943-1944 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Search for an Observatory site (correspondence). 1945 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Search for an Observatory site (correspondence). 1944-1951 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Search for an Observatory site (trips, notes and photographs). 1943-1945 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: preliminary calculations,plans,notes. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: correspondence (before and during the trip). 1923 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: correspondence (after the trip). 1923 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: A.E.D.'s eclipse articles. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: miscellaneous. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: photographs. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: photographs (astronomical). 1923 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: photography notes and bills. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Eclipse trip to Libertad, Mexico: accounts, bills. 1923 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Astronomical Observations: Astrospheric currents. 1906-1907, 1915 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Astronomical Observations: "Drawings of Comet A." 1910 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Astronomical Observations: Halley's Comet. 1910 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Astronomical Observations: Jupiter Satellites (reductions). 1909-1912 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Astronomical Observations: Jupiter Satellites (miscellaneous papers). 1909-1912 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Astronomical Observations: Latitude and longitude observations (Tucson). 1907-1924 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Astronomical Observations: Longitude of the Moon (E.W. Brown's Curve). 1919-1923 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Astronomical Observations: Meteors (correspondence). 1914-1926 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Astronomical Observations: Northern Lights. 1916-1928 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Astronomical Observations: Observations and tests (various). 1907-1925 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Astronomical Observations: Photography. 1908-1924 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Astronomical Observations: Pyrheliometer. 1907-1911 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. April-December 1909 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. January-May 1910 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. September 1910-July 1911 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. October 1911-June 1912 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. September 1913-July 1914 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. October 1914-April 1918 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Astronomical Observations: Record of Seeing. March 1920-July 1922 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Astronomical Observations: Solar energy (correspondence, clippings, brochures). 1911-1928 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Astronomical Observations: Sunset rays and dust layers. 1916-1920 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Astronomical Observations: Sunset rays and dust layers. 1916-1927 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Astronomical Observations: Time signals. 1924-1927, 1931, 1933 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Astronomical Observations: Variable stars. 1914-1929 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Astronomical Observations: Watch and clock tests. 1908-1919 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Astronomical Observations: Waves and ripples. 1914-1915 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Astronomical Observations: Wireless telegraphy and time signals. 1908-1918 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Astronomical Observations: A.E.D.'s observations of Sputnik. August 1957 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "Illusions of Vision and the Canals of Mars," (notes, references, charts, drawings, correspondence, etc.). 1906-1907 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Mars: miscellaneous articles by A.E.D. 1911-1950s (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Mars: photos and drawings. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Mars: observations and drawings. 1906-1919 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Mars: observations and drawings. 1924-1939 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Mars: observations. 1954 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Mars: Martz, E.P. (article, photographs, correspondence). 1939-1942 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Mars: record of seeing at Mt. Lowe. 1907 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Mars: photography of. 1924-1926 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Mars: articles and clippings. 1911-1923 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Mars: articles and clippings. 1924-1965 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (correspondence). 1914-1934 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (Stellar Bands). 1906-1908 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (A.E.D.'s Zodiacal map). 1912 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (computations). 1914-1915 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (early tabular material). 1914 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (map). 1914 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (map). June 13, 1915 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (photographs). 1914-1915 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (photography of). 1915-1916 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Astronomical Observation: Zodiacal Light (article). 1915 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: 1923 eclipse (61, plus 26 negatives). No Date (Box 55a and b)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: Mars (12). No Date (Box 55a and b)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: Moon (5). No Date (Box 55a and b)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: "Seven Keys to the Vaults of Heaven." No Date (Box 55a and b)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: miscellaneous. No Date (Box 55a and b)
    - Glass Plates and Slides: 1923 eclipse (4 large). 1923 (Box 55a and b)
  - Astronomy
    - Astronomers (biographical sketches, photographs, clippings). No Date (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Eclipse photographs (various). No Date (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Lantern Slides and Photographs (catalogs). No Date (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Makers of Optical Instruments (biographical sketches). No Date (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association. No Date (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Observatories (Mt. Lowe). No Date (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Observatories (photographs, clippings, brochures). No Date (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Postal First Day Issues (Trans-Polar flight and dedication of Mt. Palomar Observatory). 1924, 1948 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Star Maps. No Date (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Catalogs of Scientific Equipment
    - Bausch & Lomb; Gaertner; Keuffel & Bisser; Max Kohl A.G.; Doston Power Transmission Equipment; and A.B. Skogs. 1919-1949 (Box 57)
    - Cameras, photography. (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Clocks, timing instruments. (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Electrical equipment. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Office equipment. (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Radio. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Recording Instruments. (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Telescopes, optical instruments. (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Leeds and Northrup. 1916-1939 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Leitz. 1926-1935 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Spencer. 1923-1938 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Warner and Swasey. 1909 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Zeiss. 1909-1941 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Astronomy and Meteorology Reprints
    Dr. Douglass acquired a large number of reprints and miscellaneous publications on various scientific subjects. He also clipped articles from periodicals. Those items which came to Special Collections have been retained here for two reasons: many were written by associates, students, distinguished scientists with whome he corresponded, and all of them freflect his special interests in the fields of both astronomy and meteorology.
    They have been grouped into rather broad subjects, arranged alphabetically, but no attempt has been made to list them by author or date.
    - Air masses. (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Astronomy (general). (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Astrophysics. (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Atmospheric conditions. (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Aurora. (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Comets. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Cosmos. (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Earth. (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Eclipses. (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Instruments. (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Jupiter. (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Mayan Astronomy. (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Measurements. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Meteorology (general). (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Meteors. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Moon. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Periodicities (various). (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Planets. (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Radio. (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Rainfall and Droughts. (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Stars (general). (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Solar and terrestrial relationships. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Solar radiation and rotation. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Solar system and its activity. (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Sun. (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Solar Physics and Earthquakes, by Edward Lynch. 1928 (Box 62)
    - Southern Hemisphere Surface-air Circulation, by W.J.S. Lockyer. 1910 (Box 62)
    - Sunspots, I. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Sunspots, II. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Telescopes. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Variable Stars. (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Weather Forecasting. (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Weather and Business. (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - The Sunspot, vol. 1,2,7 (University of Santa Clara Observatory, Santa Clara, California). (Box 63)
- Series IV: Tree-Ring Materials, 1894-1966
  - Correspondence (general). 1906-1924 (Box 64)